Okay, so lets look more
carefully at this model for
accepting rejecting students.
Let's say you have a student 4 who got
a 9 on a test, but 1 on their grades.
That student gets accepted according
to our model since they are over here,
on top of the line.
But that seems wrong since the student
who got very low grades shouldn't get
accepted.
So, maybe it's too simplistic to think
that this data can be separated by just
a line, right?
Maybe the real data should
look more like this.
Or these students who
got a low test score or
low grades still do not get accepted.
So, it seems that a line
won't cut it anymore.
What's the next thing after a line?
Maybe a circle?
A circle could work.
Maybe two lines?
That could work, too.
Let's go with that.
Let's go with two lines.
And how do we find these two lines?
Again, we can do it using
gradient descent and
minimize the similar log
loss function as before.
This is called a neural network.
Now the question is,
why is this called the neural network?
Well, let's say we're working in
a very slow computer which can only do
one thing at a time.
So it's not easy to just ask,
is this point in the area
bounded by these two lines?
We have to split in two
separate questions.
The first question is,
is the point over the blue line.
Let's answer that question based on
the four black points in the graph.
We can see that for these four points,
the answers are yes, yes, no, and no.
The second question is,
is the point over the orange line?
And we can see that,
for the four points,
the answers are no, yes, no, and yes.
Now, the third question will just take
the answers from the previous two and
combine them.
So the third question is,
are the answers to questions one and
two both yes?
And we can see that for
these four points,
the answers are no, yes, no, and no.
So they are all no, except for
the one that is in the green area.
Now, let's graph each
question as a small note.
The first question is is the point
over the blue line we have
a nobody area and twin but
notes the test score and the grades.
For example, we have a student with
a test score 1 and the grades act eight.
The node plots the point and checks to
the point is on top of a black line and
returns the answer, yes or no.
The second question is similar.
We input testing grades, and the
corresponding node will plot point and
return a yes or a new depending on the
point being Top of the orange line or
not.
Now the third question, are the answers
to questions 1 and 2 both yes?
We'll just take as inputs the answers
to the two previous questions, and
return a yes if the two answers
are yes and a no otherwise.
This is known in logic as the and
operator.
Now this is where the magic happens.
If we join the nodes for these three
questions, then we get a neural network.
And if we clear it up a bit,
we have the following.
The first column is
a reinput testing grades.
In the second column is where we
check the point with coordinates,
corresponding to the test and the grades
is on top of each one of the lines.
And the third layer in which we look at
the answer from the previous layer, and
join them with the AND operator.
So this is how our neural
network will look.
Now, you may thinking something's
a little suspicious here.
The first two nodes look
like they take values and
check it at the corresponding point
is on top or below a certain line.
Where as the third node just takes
yes or no, and returns yes or no.
Is it possible to see the third
node as one of the first two?
And the answer is, yes.
So let's look at the AND
operator in more detail.
Let's actually make a little table
of what goes in and what goes out.
So, in the AND operator if we put
a yes and a yes, we get a yes.
If we input a yes and no, we get a no.
If we input a no and a yes, we get a no.
And finally if we input a no and a no.
We get a no, now we can think of
a yes as a one and a no as a zero,
in that case,
our table turns into this other one.
And now, look at this operator in which
we enter value zero and one and check if
the corresponding point with those
coordinates over or below the line.
If we look at the points with
coordinates 1, 1, we get that this point
is over the line on the green or
positive region, so we get a 1.
Now, if we look at the points with
coordinates 1, 0, we see that it's under
the line on the red or
negative region, so we get a zero.
Similarly, for
the point with coordinate 0,1,
this point is under the line so
we get a zero.
And finally, the point with coordinate
zero zero is under the line too,
so the answer is zero again.
So, this is how our final
neural network looks.
On the the left we have what's
called the input layer,
where in this case we're inputting
the test scores and the grades.
Here we have a case where the test
scores one and the grades are eight.
Then this goes through a middle layer,
called a hidden layer.
Which will help us
with our computations.
So, in here we can see that the 1 and
the 8 go become the point
with coordinates one comma eight on
the two graphs in the next layer.
In the top node, the point one
comma eight is on the green or
positive region.
So the top node emits a yes.
In the bottom node the point one comma
a is in the red or negative region.
So the bottom node emits a No.
Now, we remember that a Yes
is represented by 1 and
a No is represented by a 0.
Now the next layer,
called the output layer,
takes the values coming out of
the middle layer namely, the one and
the zero, And it locates
the point with coordinates 1, 0.
This point is in the red or
negative region of the final node,
so the output here is a no.
Thus the neural network has received
inputs The value's test equals 1 and
grades equals 8, and
it has outputted a NO.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
This is a simple neural network, but
you can see how adding more nodes in the
middle, or even more layers of nodes,
can help us map more complex areas in
the plane or even in three dimensions,
or higher dimensional spaces.
Neural networks are a very powerful
machine learning algorithm used
in most state of the art
projects such as,
facial recognition, voice recognition,
playing chess, and self driving cars.
And we call it a neural network
because these nodes resemble
neurons in the brain.
A neuron will take as input the output
of other neurons in the form of nervous
impulses and
decide to fire a nervous impulse or not.
In our case, the neuron takes this
input, the output of other neurons in
the form of numbers, and
decides to return a one or a zero.
[BLANK_AUDIO]